# Hunmin Yang (양훈민)

Personal Website Senior AI Researcher @ ADD PhD Candidate @ KAIST

Yuseong P.O. Box 35, Daejeon 34186, Republic of Korea 291 Daehak-ro, Yuseong-gu, Daejeon 34141, Republic of Korea

#### Research Interest

## • Trustworthy Machine Learning & Computer Vision

o My research focuses on developing safe and reliable artificial intelligence to enable safe model deployment in real-world applications. To achieve this, I work at the intersection of machine learning and computer vision. My current interests include transferable adversarial attacks, domain generalization, and representation learning.

#### Experience

# Agency for Defense Development (ADD)

Daejeon, Korea Jan 2020 - Present

Email: hmyang@kaist.ac.kr

Mobile: +82-10-8447-1009

Senior AI Researcher

• D-CAM: Adversarial attack & defense techniques for robust AI

• D-GEN: Synthetic data generation framework for training AI

### Agency for Defense Development (ADD)

AI Researcher

Daejeon, Korea May 2017 - Dec 2019

o D-NET: Large-scale AI inference platform with Hadoop-Spark

## Agency for Defense Development (ADD)

Specialized Research Staff (Military Service)

Daejeon, Korea Feb 2014 - May 2017

#### EDUCATION

## Korea Advance Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)

Daejeon, Korea Sep 2021 - Present

PhD in Mechanical Engineering

o Research Area: Machine Learning & Computer Vision

o Advisor: Kuk-Jin Yoon

## Korea Advance Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)

Daejeon, Korea Feb 2012 - Feb 2014

MS in Mechanical Engineering

o Research Area: 3D Sound Perception

o Advisor: Youngjin Park

## Royal Melbourne Institute of Technology (RMIT)

Exchange Student (High Distinction)

Melbourne, Australia Feb 2011 - Aug 2011

## Korea Advance Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)

BS in Mechanical Engineering (Magna Cum Laude)

Daejeon, Korea Feb 2007 - Feb 2012

## **PUBLICATIONS**

- Hunmin Yang, Jongoh Jeong, Kuk-Jin Yoon. Prompt-Driven Contrastive Learning for Transferable Adversarial Attacks. In European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2024. (Oral, top 2.3%)
- Junhyeong Cho, Kim Youwang, Hunmin Yang, Tae-Hyun Oh, Object-Centric Domain Randomization for 3D Shape Reconstruction in the Wild. In IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) Workshop on Foundation Models, 2024.
- Hunmin Yang\*, Jongoh Jeong\*, Kuk-Jin Yoon. FACL-Attack: Frequency-Aware Contrastive Learning for Transferable Adversarial Attacks. In Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2024.
- Junhveong Cho, Gilhvun Nam, Sungveon Kim, Hunmin Yang, Suha Kwak. PromptStyler: Prompt-driven Style Generation for Source-free Domain Generalization. In IEEE/CVF International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV), 2023.
- Naufal Suryanto, Yongsu Kim, Harashta Tatimma Larasati, Hyoeun Kang, Thi-Thu-Huong Le, Yoonyoung Hong, Hunmin Yang, Se-Yoon Oh, Howon Kim. ACTIVE: Towards Highly Transferable 3D Physical Camouflage for Universal and Robust Vehicle Evasion. In IEEE/CVF International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV), 2023.

- Hunmin Yang, Se-Yoon Oh, Junhyeong Jo. Synthetic Image Generation for Deep Neural Networks. In *NVIDIA GPU Technology Conference (GTC)*, 2023. (Spotlight)
- Naufal Suryanto, Yongsu Kim, Hyoeun Kang, Harashta Tatimma Larasati, Youngyeo Yun, Thi-Thu-Huong Le, **Hunmin Yang**, Se-Yoon Oh, Howon Kim. DTA: Physical Camouflage Attacks using Differentiable Transformation Network. In *IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)*, 2022.
- Jeonghun Kim, Kyungmin Lee, Hyeongkeun Lee, **Hunmin Yang**, Se-Yoon Oh. Camouflaged Adversarial Attack on Object Detector . In 21th International Conference on Control, Automation and Systems (ICCAS), 2021.
- Hunmin Yang, Se-Yoon Oh, Taewon Kim, Ki-Jung Ryu. D-GEN: A Deep Learning Data Generation Framework For Artificial Intelligence. In NVIDIA GPU Technology Conference (GTC), 2020.
- Kyungmin Lee, **Hunmin Yang**, Se-Yoon Oh. Adversarial Training on Joint Energy Based Model for Robust Classification and Out-of-Distribution Detection. In 20th International Conference on Control, Automation and Systems (ICCAS), 2020.
- Eunchong Kim, Kanghyun Park, **Hunmin Yang**, Se-Yoon Oh. Training Deep Neural Networks with Synthetic Data for Off-Road Vehicle Detection. In 20th International Conference on Control, Automation and Systems (ICCAS), 2020.
- Hyeongkeun Lee, Kyungmin Lee, **Hunmin Yang**, Se-Yoon Oh. Applying FastPhotoStyle to Synthetic Data for Military Vehicle Detection. In 20th International Conference on Control, Automation and Systems (ICCAS), 2020.
- Kanghyun Park, Hyeongkeun Lee, **Hunmin Yang**, Se-Yoon Oh. Improving Instance Segmentation using Synthetic Data with Artificial Distractors. In 20th International Conference on Control, Automation and Systems (ICCAS), 2020.
- Hunmin Yang, Se-Yoon Oh, Ki-Jung Ryu. Accelerating Distributed Deep Learning Inference on multi-GPU with Hadoop-Spark. In NVIDIA GPU Technology Conference (GTC), 2019. (Oral)
- **Hunmin Yang**, Se-Yoon Oh, Ki-Jung Ryu. Scalable Distributed Deep Learning Inference on Multi-GPU with Hadoop-Spark. In *NVIDIA GPU Technology Conference (GTC)*, 2019.
- Se-Yoon Oh, **Hunmin Yang**, Ki-Jung Ryu. Optimal Distributed Inference on Multi-GPU Processing System. In NVIDIA GPU Technology Conference (GTC), 2019.
- Se-Yoon Oh, **Hunmin Yang**, Ki-Jung Ryu. Optimal Experimental Design Approach for Machine Learning Process. In 17th International Conference on Control, Automation and Systems (ICCAS), 2017.

#### PATENTS

#### Machine Learning & Image Generation

- Hunmin Yang, Se-Yoon Oh. Training data generation method and apparatus for deep learning model. kr 10-2613781, 2023.
- Hunmin Yang, Ki-Jung Ryu, Se-Yoon Oh. Apparatus and method for deep learning based on mixing virtual and real data. kr 10-2198088, 2020.
- **Hunmin Yang**, Ki-Jung Ryu, Se-Yoon Oh. Apparatus and method for learning machine learning models based on virtual data. kr 10-2086351, 2020.
- Hunmin Yang, Se-Yoon Oh, Seongbaek Jo. Apparatus and method for enhancing learning capability for machine learning. kr 10-2053202, 2019.
- Hunmin Yang, Ki-Jung Ryu, Se-Yoon Oh. Method and apparatus of improving self-supervised learning performance utilizing synthesized data. kr 10-2032519, 2019.
- Hunmin Yang, Ki-Jung Ryu, Se-Yoon Oh. Method and Apparatus of adding artificial object for improving performance in detecting object. kr 10-1972095, 2019.
- **Hunmin Yang**, Se-Yoon Oh, Seongbaek Jo. Apparatus and method for generating learning image in game engine-based machine learning. kr 10-1947650, 2019.

## AI Security & Adversarial Robustness

- Se-Yoon Oh, **Hunmin Yang**, Hyeongkeun Lee, Kyungmin Lee, Jeonghun Kim. Method and Apparatus for optimizing adversarial patch, computer-readable storage medium and computer program. kr 10-2445215, 2022.
- Hyeongkeun Lee, Jeonghun Kim, Kyungmin Lee, **Hunmin Yang**, Se-Yoon Oh. Method and Apparatus for optimizing adversarial patch, computer-readable storage medium and computer program. kr 10-2414146, 2022.

- Jeonghun Kim, Se-Yoon Oh, Hyeongkeun Lee, Kyungmin Lee, **Hunmin Yang**. Apparatus and method for optimizing adversarial patch based on natural pattern for stealthiness against human vision system. kr 10-2380154, 2022.
- Hyeongkeun Lee, Hunmin Yang, Jeonghun Kim, Kyungmin Lee, Se-Yoon Oh. Method, apparatus computer-readable storage medium and computer program for determining adversarial patch position. kr 10-2360070, 2022.

#### Big Data & Database

- Hunmin Yang, Ki-Jung Ryu, Se-Yoon Oh. Method and apparatus of building NoSQL database for signal processing. kr 10-2002360, 2019.
- **Hunmin Yang**, Ki-Jung Ryu, Se-Yoon Oh. Method and apparatus of building inverse index DB for high speed searching of moving picture object. kr 10-2014267, 2019.

#### Honors and Awards

### Selected as Oral Presentation (top 2.3%)

 ${\rm Oct}\ 2024$ 

- In European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV)
  - o Prompt-Driven Contrastive Learning for Transferable Adversarial Attacks

#### National Grant for Defense Research and Development

Dec 2021

- From the Chief Director of DAPA
  - $\circ\,$  Synthetic Data Generation for Defense AI

#### Defense Science Award

Aug 2019

- From the Chief Research Director of ADD
  - o Improving Distributed Multi-GPU Computing for Large-scale Video Analytics

## High Achievement Award

Aug 2018

- From the Chief Research Director of ADD
  - o Big Data Platform Development and Synthetic Data Generation

### **Excellent Paper Award**

Mar 2013

- From the Korea Society for Noise and Vibration Engineering (KSNVE)
  - o Sweet Spot Analysis of Linear Array System by Geometrical Approach

## Scholarship for Academic Excellence

Jun 2007

- From the Korea Human Resource Development Scholarship Association
  - $\circ\,$  Outstanding Academic Performance

# Scholarship for Academic Excellence

2007-2014

- From the Korean Government
  - Tuition free for all semesters in KAIST (BS & MS)

## Professional Services

#### • Academic Reviewer

- IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)
- $\circ\,$  IEEE/CVF International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)
- European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV)

#### • Technology Transfer

- $\circ$  Synthetic data generation for training AI models  $\to$  SI Analytics, Jcorp System, JEIOS
- $\circ$  Physical adversarial camouflage generation for attacking AI models  $\to$  SmartM2M
- $\circ\,$  Big data platform for large-scale AI model inference  $\to$  XiiLAB